(ホムラ)いったい何の騒ぎだ？
What is all this ruckus?!
(ダンゾウ)暁の攻撃が始まったんだ。
(ホムラ)ダンゾウ。
The Akatsuki has begun its assault.
Danzo...
(コハル)暁の攻撃とは本当なのか？
Is it true about
the Akatsuki attacking?!
(ダンゾウ)ああ
攻め込んできたのは➡
Yes, the one who has attacked
is Pain, their leader...
自来也を倒した暁のリーダー ペイン。
who defeated Jiraiya.
自来也を亡き者にしたうえで➡
You're saying that he has personally
come after the Hidden Leaf,
すぐさま木ノ葉に
自ら乗り込んできたというのか？
so soon after he killed Jiraiya?
ああ ヤツらは➡
Yes... They've been hunting
Jinchuriki hosts
尾獣を集めるために
人柱力を狩っている。
in order to accumulate
Tailed Beasts.
砂の一尾を含め
すでに大半の人柱力が➡
It's believed that in addition to
the One-Tail of the Sand,
most of the Jinchuriki have fallen
into their hands.
ヤツらの手に落ちたと思われる。
(コハル)それでは ヤツの目的は？
Then... their target is...
四代目火影の遺産
うずまきナルト。
The Fourth Hokage's legacy...
Uzumaki Naruto!
しかし 五代目は この危機に➡
And yet, despite the danger,
the Fifth Hokage is trying
to summon Naruto back.
さらに ナルトを
里に呼び戻そうとしている。
そんなことをしたら➡
Such a thing...
is like pouring oil onto a fire!
まさに 火に
油を注ぐようなものではないか。
そうだ このまま 五代目の
言うことを聞いていたら➡
Yes... If we keep listening
to the Fifth...
木ノ葉は滅びる。
the Hidden Leaf will be destroyed!
(みんな)うわぁ～！
(紅)なに？
What was that?!
(シカマル)ダメです 外に出ちゃ。
Stop! You mustn't go outside!
Shikamaru! What's going on?!
シカマル これはいったい？
暁が のりこんできた。
The Akatsuki has entered our territory.
チッ。
紅先生 ちょっと
下がっていてもらえますか。
Kurenai-sensei, can you step back?
くたばれ。
Drop dead!
伏せろ！
Get down!
あなた 大丈夫？
Are you all right?
オレは大丈夫だ。
I'm fine. But Sensei,
please use the underground tunnel
それより 先生は
地下通路を通って避難所へ。
and go to the evacuation shelter.
オレが途中まで警護する。
I'll escort you part way.
先生と そのお腹の子に
何かあったら➡
If anything should happen
to you or the baby,
オレは アスマに顔向けできねえ。
I wouldn't be able to face Asuma.
シカマル。
Shikamaru...
(ガマ吉)あれ？ ナルトは？
Huh? Where's Naruto?
(フカサク)わからんか？
(ガマ吉)えっ？
Can't you tell?
Heh?
よく見ろ。
Look carefully!
ナルト！
Naruto... I didn't notice him at all.
まったく わからんかった。
やりおるわい！
あそこまで➡
Impressive...
Look how far he's come
in being one with nature.
自然と一体化することが
できるようになった。
(ナルト)とりあえず
この修業は終わりかな。
Well, that's about it for this training.
I gotta take care of some business!
オレ ちょっと 用足してくるからさ。
危ない フカサク様！
Watch out, Fukasaku-sama!
イテッ！
Oww... Are you all right, Fukasaku-sama?
イテテテ… 大丈夫ですか？ フカサク様。
《自来也ちゃんの目は
間違いなかったのう。
Jiraiya-chan's eyes were
not wrong.
あの子は 自来也ちゃん以上に
強くなる子じゃ！》
That boy will become even
stronger than Jiraiya-chan!
コレッ！ はよどかんか！
重たいわい！
Hey! Hurry and get off me!
You're heavy!
ナルトのアホ！
Naruto... You idiot!
(サクラ)チョウジ！
Choji!
I brought you pills.
(チョウジ)丸薬を持ってきた！
あぁ ありがとう。
Thanks.
What is...?!
これって…。
イテェよ…。
オレの足が…。
Oh, the pain...
My leg...
What is all of this?
(サクラ)なんなの？ これ。
サクラさん！ ちょうどよかった！
Sakura-san! You're just in time.
ここの陣頭指揮を
お願いします！
Please take command.
え？ シズネさんは？
シズネさんはいません。
Huh? What about Shizune-san?
She's not here.
そうだった… まだ検死中よね。
Oh, that's right. She's in
the middle of the autopsy.
あまりにも人数が多くて
医療忍者たちも混乱気味で。
There are so many wounded,
even the Medical Ninja are in
a state of confusion.
誰か現場をまとめて
指示しないと…。
We need someone to take charge
and give us orders.
指示って…。
Take charge?!
《サクラ : こんなにたくさんの命を
預かるなんて…。
To be responsible for so many lives...
こんなとき 綱手様なら…》
At a time like this,
Tsunade-sama would...
ほら これ食べて
がんばれば。
Here. Why not eat this
and just do your best?
それは 私じゃなくて
ケガ人に使うものよ。
This is for the wounded, not me!
歩ける人は？ 自分で歩いて
避難所のほうへ移動してください。
If you're able to walk,
please go to the evacuation shelter.
Shortly, many more
seriously wounded will arrive!
まもなく ここには
もっと多くのケガ人がやってきます。
すぐに治療が必要な
重傷者は赤。
Those who are critical will be red!
少しなら治療を待てる人は 黄色。
If treatment can wait,
they are yellow!
軽症の人は 緑のリボンをつけて
振り分けてください。
And those with minor injuries
are green!
Tag them with ribbons
and separate them!
は はい！
さすがだね。
Y-Yes, ma'am.
You're... amazing.
ボクも戻る。
ここは任せたよ。
I'm going back!
You're in charge here.
Yes.
うん！
大丈夫ですか？
呼吸はできますか？
Are you all right?
Can you breathe?
what did I really lose that day?
ano hi honto ni ushinatta monotte nan dattakke
for the life of me I can't remember
tou ni wasureteshimatta yo
we slowly lost sight of each other in the twilight
yuugure de futari sukoshizutsu mienakunatteitte
and yet we're stuck here unable to go home
sore nanoni bokura kaerezu ni ita
weak, frail souls lost in the world
dokoka ni kowaresou na moroi kokoro
we act strong to hide their fragility
tsuyogaru kotoba de ootte kakushiteru
hide their fragility
ootte kakushiteru
so farewell, but even forced apart
sayonara aenakunattatte
our stories go on
bokura wa tsuzuki ga aru kara
even in a world without you, I run
kimi no inai sekai datte hashiru yo
to someday get past the pain
itsuka no itami mo koete
Power to Believe
All right.
I will return to call Naruto back.
わかった！
ほんでは ナルトを呼びに帰る。
I'm counting on you!
(綱手)頼んだぞ。
Stop!
(コハル)ダメじゃ！
ナルトは 妙木山に置いておけ。
Leave Naruto on Mount Myoboku.
What?!
なんだ!?
We understand that
it's the Akatsuki's leader
(ホムラ)今 里に攻め入っているのは
暁のリーダーだと聞いた。
who has attacked our village.
どうしてそれを？
How did you find out?
We heard it from Danzo.
ダンゾウから聞いたのじゃ。
しかも 人柱力のナルトを
狙っているというではないか。
Moreover, they are after
Naruto's Jinchuriki power.
So what of it?
それがどうした？
The last time, we gave you
the benefit of the doubt.
前回は 大目に見たが
今回ばかりは 話が別じゃ。
But not this time.
ナルトは まだ子供。
Naruto is still a child.
侵入者は 自来也を
倒したというではないか。
This is the assailant who
brought Jiraiya down!
ナルトがやられ 九尾がヤツらの手に
渡れば それこそ…。
If Naruto is taken and
the Nine-Tails falls into their hands...
Wha-?! What are you doing?!
うぅ… 何をする！
Don't try to protect me!
Naruto, you too, stop!
((綱手 : 私をかばうな！
ナルト！ もうやめろ！
If you die... your dreams,
everything will be gone.
死んだら何もかも
夢も何もないんだよ！
Humph... I'm all right.
ヘッ！ 大丈夫だってばよ！
Enough! Move! And run!
もういいから どけ！ 逃げろ！
Until I become Hokage...
オレは 火影になるまで
ぜってぇ…。
I'll...
never die!
死なねえからよ！
エロ仙人の敵は オレが討つ。
I will avenge Pervy Sage!
じっとなんて
してらんねえんだよ。
I can't just sit around doing nothing!
しんみりするのは ちと違うのう。
However... I guess I shouldn't
wallow in sadness.
My duty is to be a model
for the next generation
わしらの役目は 次の世代のために
手本となり 手助けをすること。
and to help them out.
For that, I'd happily give my life.
そのためなら 笑って命をかける。
(フカサク)あの子が 自来也ちゃんを
まっすぐに慕っとったのが➡
I can see that child truly loved
and admired Jiraiya-chan.
ようわかった。
I can't help but hope that
he is the Child of Prophecy.
予言の子は
あの子であってほしいと➡
そう願わずには おれんのう。
For Jiraiya-chan has entrusted
his all to that child.
(自来也ちゃんは すべてを
あの子に託したんじゃからな))
こ これ！ 離さぬか綱手。
Y-You... Unhand us, Tsunade!
お前 わしら相談役に向かって
何様のつもりじゃ！
How dare you raise your hand
against us counselors...
Who do you think you are?!
アンタらこそ 何様だ！
How long do you intend to
treat him like a child?
いつまでも
アイツを子供扱いしやがって！
What?!
木ノ葉の意志は受け継がれ
そして育っている。
The will of the Hidden Leaf
has been passed on
and it's growing!
ナルトは今
自来也を越えようとしている。
Naruto is striving to surpass
Jiraiya this very minute!
アイツは 木ノ葉の隠し持つ➡
He's not a hidden weapon
to be used by the Hidden Leaf
as a deterrent to war!
戦争抑止の道具なんかじゃない。
He is a ninja who has sworn
to protect the Hidden Leaf...
木ノ葉を守る一人の忍➡
うずまきナルトだ！
He is Uzumaki Naruto!
自来也 そして猿飛先生や
砂のチヨ様にあって➡
Jiraiya, Sarutobi-sensei and
Chiyo-sama of the Sand
アンタたちにないもの…。
all had what you two lack.
それが何だかわかるか？
Do you know what that is?
((今日は キミらに
わしの作った詞を➡
Today, I am going to recite
a poem I wrote.
朗読して聞かせよう。
ぜひ覚えて帰ってもらいたい。
I want you to remember it
when you go home.
ブ～ ブ～！ そんなのノーサンキュー！
No thanks! I can't memorize
stuff like that.
覚えらんねえし！
アハハッ いえてる！
Couldn't agree more.
(イルカ)こらっ ナルト！
Hey! Naruto!
Iruka-sensei!
ゲッ… イルカ先生！
ハハハ… もうよい イルカ。
That's all right, Iruka.
They have a point.
こやつらの言うことも
もっともじゃ。
Ah... I-I'm sorry.
アハッ… す すみません。
そうじゃのう。
今はまだ すべてを覚えろとも➡
Let's see. I won't tell you to
memorize the entire poem.
意味を理解しろとも言わん。
Nor will I expect you to
understand its meaning.
ただ キミらが大きくなったとき➡
But when you are grown,
あのじじいが こんなこと
言っていたと 思い出してほしい。
I want you to think back and
recall the words of this old man.
It's about a way of thinking
キミらの将来 きっと
役に立つ考えかたの一つ➡
that is sure to be useful
to you in your future,
火の意思についてじゃ。
and concerns the will of fire.
木ノ葉舞うところに 火は燃ゆる。
In the place where leaves dance...
The fire burns...
The shadow of the fire shines
on the village...
火の影は 里を照らし➡
Once again, new leaves sprout.
また 木ノ葉は芽吹く。
(チヨ)くだらぬ年寄りどもが作った
この忍の世界に➡
Amidst this Shinobi world created
by us foolish old people...
I am glad that
a person like you showed up...
お前のようなヤツが
現れてくれて うれしい。
かつて わしのしてきたことは➡
The things I did in the past
were nothing but mistakes...
間違いばかりじゃった。
しかし 最後の最後になって➡
But... in my last hour,
it seems I shall finally be able
to do the right thing.
正しいことが
やっとできそうじゃ。
砂と木ノ葉…。
The Village Hidden in the Sand and...
The Village Hidden in the Leaves.
これからの未来は➡
The future is likely to be different
from the way things were
in our time...
わしらのときとは
違ったものになろう。
カカシの言っていた
お前の不思議な力。
Your mysterious power
that Kakashi spoke of...
その力が
未来を大きく変えるじゃろう。
That power is likely to alter
the future greatly...
(今までにない火影になってな…))
when you become a Hokage
like none before...
猿飛先生や 砂のチヨ様にあって➡
What Sarutobi-sensei and
Chiyo-sama of the Sand had,
and what you two lack.
That is...
アンタたちにないもの それは…。
信じる力だ！
The power to believe!
私の祖父
初代火影がアンタたちを信じ➡
In the same way that
my grandfather, the First Hokage,
木ノ葉を託したように。
believed in you and entrusted
the Hidden Leaf to you...
(綱手)今度はアンタたちが子供を信じ
託す番だ！
It is time for you to believe,
and entrust to the next generation!
好きにせい。
Do as you please.
(シズネ)綱手様！
Tsunade-sama!
何かわかったのか？
はい。
Did you learn anything?
Yes!
これです。
何だ？
This here!
What is it?
チャクラの信号を受け取る
受信機のようなものです。
It seems to be a receiver
for chakra signals.
ペインの検死体のあちこちに
刺さっていました。
Pain's corpse had these inserted
throughout his body.
受信機？
フカサク様のお話からすると➡
A receiver?!
According to what
Fukasaku-sama said,
ペイン６人全員の体や顔に➡
all six Pains had these stuck
in their bodies and faces.
これと同じものが
刺さっていたことになります。
つまり ６人とも➡
Does this mean that
the six Pains receive
何かしらのチャクラの信号を
全身で受け取り➡
some kind of chakra signal through
their bodies, and then take action?
行動しているということか。
まだ そこまでハッキリしてません。
That part isn't clear yet.
受信機 それとも
互いにチャクラを送信し合う➡
A receiver... Or they use it
to transmit chakra to each other.
無線のようなものか。
Something wireless...
そして
これが今まさに反応していて…。
Also, this has definitely been activated.
それが ペインの強さの秘密に
つながっているはずです。
This must be connected to
the secret of Pain's strength.
尋問班からの情報と合わせて
早急に解明します。
Together with the data
the Interrogation Corps gathers,
we'll figure this out.
情報部からの連絡によると
敵はナルトを捜している。
According to the Intel Division,
the enemy is looking for Naruto.
この里に侵入してきた敵は
まず間違いなくペインだ。
This enemy, who infiltrated the village,
is undoubtedly Pain.
ペインが？
Pain...
すべてをフカサク様にも
連絡しておいたほうがいいな。
We must tell Fukasaku-sama
of the situation in detail.
連絡蛙よ ナルトを呼ぶついでに➡
Messenger frog!
When you go to summon Naruto,
このことも伝えてくれ。
わかった！
relay this message as well.
Understood!
シズネは検死の情報をもって
尋問班と接触し➡
Shizune, take the data
from the autopsy,
collaborate with Interrogation Corps
and figure out just who Pain is!
ペインが何者か解明しろ！
はい！
暗部 ろ班は シズネの護衛。
Yes, ma'am!
Anbu Black Ops cell B will provide
Shizune with a protective escort!
そのついでに
尋問部隊のガードに回れ。
Subsequently, you are to guard
the Interrogation Corps!
ヤツらを近づけるな！
はっ！
Do not allow the enemy
to get near them!
Yes, ma'am!
私は屋上で情報を待ちつつ➡
I will wait for further news
on the rooftop,
カツユを通じて全ケガ人の治療を行う。
and I will provide treatment for
all the wounded through Katsuyu.
里を全力で守る！
I will use all my power to
protect the village!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
よし オレもさっそく
フカサク様のとこに行かなくちゃ！
Right! I must rush to Fukasaku-sama too!
まったく役に立たぬヤツらだ。
They are so useless.
All they've done is grow old...
ムダに歳だけとりおって。
逆に綱手に丸め込まれるとはな。
So Tsunade persuaded them
to her side instead...
だがこれで
九尾は閉じ込めておける。
But now, the Nine-Tails
can be kept caged up.
ハァッ ハァッ ハァッ…。
(小南)もう一度聞く。
うずまきナルトは どこにいる？
I'll ask you once more.
Where is Uzumaki Naruto?
くたばれ。
Go to hell!
言え うずまきナルトは
この里にいるのか いないのか。
Speak. Is Uzumaki Naruto
in this village or not?
どっちだ？
し 知らない。
Which is it?
I-I don't know...
コイツ 術を吸い取りやがる。
This guy... He sucked up the jutsu!
ならば 直接攻撃しかないな。
Then we'll have to engage
in direct combat.
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu.
これから 木ノ葉にいる忍や➡
Starting now, attach yourself
to every ninja and citizen
一般の者たちも含めて
全員につけ！
in the Hidden Leaf Village!
私のチャクラを受け取り
全員のケガを治療しろ！
Take in my chakra and use it
to treat all their injuries!
(カツユ)
どうやら里のピンチみたいですね。
It seems the village is in dire straits.
いいから さっさとしろ。
Never mind, just go.
わかりました。
I understand.
何がなんでも この里は守る！
I will protect this village,
no matter what happens!
(綱手)火影の名にかけて！
I swear upon my title of Hokage!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
九尾の人柱力の
居場所を吐け。
Tell me where the Jinchuriki
of the Nine-Tails is...
でなければ 殺す。
Or else, I'll kill you.
《この紋 そうか コイツが暁！》
This crest...
I see... So he's from the Akatsuki.
さあ 言え。
Speak up.
《ナルト！》
Naruto...
お前のようなヤツに
何も話すつもりはない。
I have no intention of telling
you anything!
そうか。 なら 用はない。
I see... Then I have no use for you.
(カカシ)派手に暴れて注意を引いて➡
You create a loud diversion,
かたや 陰で捜索か。
so that you can investigate
from the shadows, eh?
カカシさん！
Kakashi!
そこの負傷者を連れて
退いてください。
Please take the wounded one
and get away.
ここは オレに任せて。
Leave this scene to me.
わ わかりました。
Roger!
《お願いします カカシさん》
Good luck, Kakashi!
これでサシだ。
Now it's just the two of us.
ならば お前に聞く。
Then I'll ask you.
Where is the Nine-Tails?
九尾は どこだ？
お前のやっていることは
まったくのムダだよ。
What you're doing is totally pointless.
ここの人間は
そこらの里とは違う。
The people of this village are
different from your average village.
例え 自分の命を
落とすことになっても➡
Even if it means dying,
仲間を売るヤツは…。
there's not a single
one of us who would
一人もいない。
sell out a comrade.
yesterday, I cut my hair a little
kinou sukoshi kami wo kitta
if I don't say it, I'm sure
iwanakareba kitto
nobody will realise, I guess
daremo kizukanai darou kedo
for a long time
nankagetsu ka bun no
I looked
watashi ga yuka ni
at what fell down on the floor
okkochita no wo mita
I closed my eyes
me wo tojite
and I could hear the sound of rain
kikoete kita ame no oto
even from above the clouds, I'm sure
kumo no ue demo kitto
take out a pair of scissors
hasami mochidashite
we're waiting for the light
hikari wo matteiru
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide koide
pedal, and come on
koideiku yo
right now, right now, right now, right now, right now
imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu
bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha
pedal
koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
Next Episode
(ブレイン二世)無限時計は
我らが 手中にあり。
Pain displays his overwhelming powers
振幅制限器も 残りわずか。
by wiping out the Leaf reinforcements.
(ジャックポット)もう さっさと
片づけちゃいましょうよ。 ニョホホホ。
Despite their efforts, the Leaf Ninja are gradually cornered.
(レーサー)更なる破壊と終末。 フフフ。
Those who fight for the village...
And those who fight to protect their loved ones...
(コブラ)この世界に
終末を もたらすには➡
As they fight past their own limits,
まだ 足りんものがある。
what possible strategy can they make?
(グリムリーパー)風が弱い。
破壊の淵からの風が…。
Pain vs Kakashi
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Pain vs Kakashi"